Episode 7
What's wrong with hating family get-together?!
how do you tie this...
How to tie a tie
Good morning
Wow you're wearing a tie!  How unusual!
Today's the my father's "san kaiki" (3rd anniversary of death)
Why is it "san kaiki" even though he died 2 years ago?
Um...
Do you think that tie is ok?
What about it?
I think it's still black tie for "san kaiki"...
Sheesh, anniversary service is such a nuisance...
I say it nicely and not even a thanks
For "san kaiki", black tie is appropriate
Thank you for coming
- Don't mention it
- Here have some
Shinsuke, pour me a glass
- Um, even with your busy schedule, thank..
- You know Ikuyo-san...
Only Shinsuke needs to get married now
As the elder son, only you can continue on Kuwano's name
Your late father,
even on that night (he passed away),
was worried about you
Well, yeah
How about Yoshikawa's daughter?
Her husband passed away last year
Fumi's husband is still alive and well!
But shinsuke...
you know you're not in a position turn away people with previous marriage experience
Yes I know
Don't worry it's ok!
Marriage happens by fate
All of a sudden,
one day a good prospect can appear out of nowhere!
It would be nice if that was the case...
It's ok don't worry!
Ikuyo-san, how about living with Shinsuke until then?
No thank you!
Not with this cold selfish guy
How about living with Keiko?
Well that would be 100 times better
Since Yumi is there too
That's right
I wish you'd live with us too
- Right, honey?
- Uh.. umm yeah.
Why do they always say the same thing every time we meet?
It's because you're making them.
Hey honey
- What kind of reaction was that?
- Hrmm what?
Your face changed
You don't want to live with her, right?
No that's not it
Don't worry
I have no plan to leave my current home
But you'll let me live in an ash vase in your house after I die, right?
Yes, by all means
I have work, so I'll get going
What?
You don't need a ride?
I want to get away from these people as soon as possible
Later
Even in an ash vase,
I don't want to live with him
You're going to have separate entrances?
Of course
Even though it's a multi-family home,
we still need our prviacy
Why do you need two entrances for one house?
Inside, we can build a door that connects two units
Isn't it nice just that fact that we'll be living together
We run into this issue even at work
Today is an aging society,
so we'll be seeing more houses with 2 generations living together
Maybe we should build a ring inside so they can duke it out
Ring instead of a living (room) huh...
After seeing these,
it makes me want to avoid living with them after marrying
Well my parents don't want to live with me anyway
Aren't you forgetting something?
After marrying, it's not just your own parents
You now have the in-laws too
Ah that's true
When you get married, the number of parents and relatives,
even by simple math doubles
It's bad enough putting up with your own parents
I think it would be nice to play a good daughter in-law
saying, "mother~"
You look like the type who will poison her in-law
Let's stop chatting and talk about work
Ah sorry
I can't seem to focus today
What?
I think it's summer fatigue
Suffering from summer fatigue?
Yes
Me too
Huh?
I feel tired and have no energy
This is the first time I've seen a doctor describe her own symptom to a patient
Anybody can suffer from summer fatigue
Having a good routine,sleeping, eating properly...
and drinking regularly...
is the only way to beat it
- I'm already doing that
- Please continue to do it
Doctor is powerless, huh
Are you incapable of not saying asinine things when you're being examined?
I see you still have energy left to get angry
I need to recharge before the next patient so please...
Looks like I got worse after coming here
Excuse me
Isn't it a bit hot in here?
I'm sorry
Somebody said it's too cold...
- You
- Yes
I thought I asked to raise the temperature...
I did raise it...
I'm cold
Other say it's hot...
Nevermind
OK
Please
What are you doing here?
I have something to tell you
I'm busy
Don't you have a moment to talk?
No
- Please come in
- Huh?
There's a problem with the diagnosis
I'll explain it to you
Please come this way
I'm sorry
Who is that?
It's my Dad.
Excuse me.
Please take care of yourself
Thank you
Kekkon Dekinai Otoko
Translation: InCyphe (-.,-);
You put in the desired budget this morning right?
Yes
They decided to have separate entrances
I don't know what to do...
Kaneda updated his site
At the bar I frequent
I tried a new cocktail
As usual, goofing around and not working
I guess he's got nothing to worry about
I'm going to the bathroom
Kaneda-san's homepage?
Yup
I'm looking at it now
You see the lady's hand in the photo?
Eh?
That bracelet...
What are you looking at?
Mmm...
We only met once!
I don't care if it is Kaneda
I'm more curious why you didn't tell me about it
Well let's drop this now
You're the one who ratted me out!
Hey
Can I ask you something?
This guy...
said he won't live with my parents if we get married
Wha.. you guy's are getting married?
No
What's the point of this if we're not marrying?
Marrying, not marrying is not the point.
It's the way you think.
I'm a bit surprised by it
Me too
If my boyfriend told me he doesn't want to live with my parents
that would be depressing
Let me ask this
Are you willing to live with your husband's Mom?
I pass~
I don't want to get nagged by Mother in-law
It depends on the person
If my husband-to-be is a proper person,
then his mother has to be one too, no?
I don't see any problem living together in that case
Well said~
You're talking about ideal
Who cares~  It's not going to happen for awhile anyway
Excuse me
Sorry
This too
What's going on?
Sorry,
Don't ask why, but can I stay here tonight?
Sure you can but...
Why are you avoiding your father?
He probably wants me to go on omiai (date)
He says it looks bad to stay single past 35
so he's always nagging
So why not just go on omiai?
I want to go on one too...
I never liked any news father came to tell me
Saying stuff like how sincerity is the sole best quality,
and...
that wives should be stay-at-home Mom
Must have old view of marriage
He says how a relative gave birth to two kids,
and how that's being a better daughter to him
Well all parents say stuff like that
My Mom passed away 3 years ago
Really?
Since losing her, he has become more stubborn and nosy
Ah
-Ah, from the hospital....
-No, you're mistaken
No, it's you!
Ah.. yeah yeah...
You shouldn't drink alcohol
Why do you say that...
You have an illness
Ah~
I don't mean to be nosy
but what illness do you have?
It's none of your business
It's not
But I can't let a sick person drink
- Do you need a spoon?
- No
- Do you have a point card?
Eh?
I'll just tell you the truth
You know,
I was in the hopsital for just summer fatigue,
and ran into your daughter,
and just went along with her story
What's your relationship with Natsumi?
There's no relationship
If there's nothing between you two,
how come you lied for her?
We just happened to know each other
Excuse me
Eh?
What now?
I have a favor to ask
Huh?
Would you please listen to me?
I'm kind of busy
What's this?
It's a volume mascara
Ah~ so this is what people use~
It's popular among young people
Mmm~ young people huh
Hello?
Hello
Good morning
Something wrong?
Umm...
Can we meet today?
Huh?
With me?
Well yes
What for?
Do we need a reason to meet?
Eh?
I really need to see you
Ok
Bye
What's wrong?
No, it's nothing
Ah
- Good morning
That's where you were?
Well, I meet you at "A to Z" cafe
Wha~
Was that call from Kuwano-san?
Yup
That wasn't anything to hide about...
I wasn't really hiding
You're meeting him?
For some reason, he wants to see me
Is it a date?
Probably not?
But he looked kind of awkward
What if he proposes to you?
No way
Doctor
Lentocan seems finished.  Should I bring it here?
Yup, sure
Ok
Ah sorry
I'll be out until the afternoon patients
Huh?
Something going on?
Is it a date?
Huh?
What are you talk about...
It's not
Ouch
Excuse me
Hello
Would you like to order?
Ah
Ice royal milk tea please
Ok
Ah that's right,
I'm sorry about what happened yesterday
No problem
Umm...
Why are you avoiding your father?
He probably wants me to go on omiai
Nothing wrong with that...
you being your age and all
It's still better that there's talk of omiai than nothing
I don't want to hear that from you
You being the only daughter,
I think it would be nice to show him his grand kid's face
And also,
you shouldn't complain even if the prospect has preivous marriage experience
You brought me out here to tell me that?
Your late mother,
is probably very worried too
I told you my Mom passed away?
I told him that
Since you didn't want to listen to me,
I asked him to bring you out here
How did you two end up conspiring?
We never conspired
This guy was so persistent,
so I gave in and cooperated
What a way to put it...
But that's the truth
But for someone so reluctant,
you did a great job telling her everything on my behalf
Well I just told what I heard
It didn't have to be this complicated...
You came here to talk about marriage
- Well yeah
- Forget it
Sorry for being a bad daughter
Is this how you treat other people too?
Yes
No, I only do it to you two
Well then,
- I'll express my gratitude later...
- Don't worry about it
Please cancel that
Always meddling...
Bye
Why don't you want to listen to me?
Ok I'll listen,
but hurry up
Is that the attitude for listening to a father?
What kind of person are you going to set me up with?
You always like the government workers anyway
Always the same type
Forget it
Just go
Oh really?
Excuse me
Kaneda?
Natsumi won't listen to me
Is that so
What more now?
Hotel is this way
Well I'm going this way
Won't you at least listen to me?
...about what I want to tell Natsumi?
Why me...
It won't hurt to listen!
I guess
But
I want to tell Natsumi myself
Please make sure you don't slip your tongue
Don't worry,
I never talk to her anyway
Never?
Yes
What's this~
this isn't a date~
Sorry for letting you down~
But why is Kuwano-san listening to your father's concerns?
He's twisted and timid,
so he caves into anybody more stubborn than him
Ah!
Drinking beer by himself!
Hello?
Why don't you come over here?
Huh?
Left, left
Nah forget it
If you sit there by yourself...
I won't be able to enjoy myself
What a total disaster that was,being caught in between their fight
Things got worse thanks to somebody...
Like father like daughter huh
So what did your father want to tell you?
It's about omiai
You're wrong
Huh?
He told you something?
Well yeah
Well then you should say it
He wants to tell her directly
Why are you being loyal to him anyway?
He just wants to side with my opponent
Ah~
But I was so surprised,
To think that her father had such secret
Stop egging us on and just tell us!
It's secret!
Why is that?
Forget it!
So you get into this kind of argument everyday
when you get married huh
No one is going to marry you!
I'm talking in general
I don't think this happens in general...
- Waited long?
- Yep
You look great today
Really?
You look great too
Thank you
Welcome
Ah
Hello
Yes
I'll have the usual... double!
Hey
Do you want to meet my parents?
Isn't it a bit early?
I want to introduce you to my Dad
No?
He wants to build a house with high ceiling~..
I want to meet him
Really?
I'm so happy~
Ah you're finally here
Please wait a minute
What?
I bought this on my way home
I didn't think I can finish them
But why me?
No special meaning
I was buying mine anyway
Well in return, can you tell me what Natsumi-san's father said?
No
If you make two entrances, the parents' kitchen will get too dark
You're right
What about we move it upstair?
No
Sorry
That client from the other day
the father is fighting back
So I guess he wants only one entrance?
That's right
In the end, the parents hold the purse string
Until they decide, can you the stop the work?
But I was working on it...
Sorry, I'll make some coffee~
There's a bon odori (Bon festival) at Mariama Center tonight
I hear there will be street vendors
Since you have time, why don't you go?
Boring~
Kuwano-san didn't tell me after all
It's ok.  Just drop it.
Doesn't it bother you?
If my Dad changes his old ways,
then maybe I'll listen to him
Your Dad sounds like a diffcult character...
Why can't men like Dad and Kuwano-san be honest?
Isn't that too small a sample?
That's true
Ah
Sample no. 2
He's catching goldfish by himself...
Is he going to raise them?
Ah~
That's too bad
That's not going to work
Sir, one more
Ok
Here
First you have to check the front,
and make sure the glued side faces up
If not, then the water will collect and rip
Then get close...
Pick a target, and put the net in angle
As you zone in on the fish,
you put the net underneath
The important thing is
not to move clumsily
The problem begins here
You have to control the fish and water,
so the movement of the fish doesn't rip the net
And put the fish on the net
I did it!
Thank you sir!
Ah that's too bad...
One more
You came last year too right?
This one's on me
Good luck!
Shall we go?
Let's go
Can I just buy it?
Welcome~  How many?
Welcome
I'll have the usual
Ok
- Welcome
- Six people
Ah.. well...
We have seats here and there, separated...
It's separate tables...
Shall we go somewhere else?
I'm sorry
Let's go
Hello
What now?
No,
I don't have any
I just wanted to,
give this to Natsumi
But with what happened and all,
I'd like you to have it
I don't have any reason to accept it
I came here just to give it to you
just-to-give-it to you
Would you mind waiting a moment?
As a return...
Ah.. what's this?
They're meat-filled buns
Here
Ah...
I can't eat all these
Then I'll have one
Ok
Ittadakimasu
Delicious
Did you tell it to Natsumi?
I didn't
Eh, why not?
You told me not to
But people tell anyway
What are you talking about
Fine,
I'll tell her
You don't need to tell!
I don't understand
Ah!
Michiru you are so fast!
Fast, really?
I am pretty good
well that's that
I'm leaving
Is that ok really?
Ah, Kuwano-san
Ah
Ah you caught one
It's so cute
Please go catch one more
Huh?
He's going to be lonely
He'll want a partner
You don't understand the trouble I went through to catch just one
It's for his sake
Did you throw up?
Yes
It's a mild food poisoning
Nothing major
Food poisoning?
What did you eat?
Ah
Did you eat something weird at that restaurant?
No I didn't
Last night I had steaks..
Ah
What is it?
I ate the meat-filled buns from the neighbor
but it hadn't been in the fridge
That's no good, if you don't keep them in fridge in this weather
Well I'll prescribe you some medicine
Thank you very much
Ah
What is it?
Your father ate it too
By now, he's probably...
Well, I don't care
Really?
Well then
Please wait a minute
He's not picking his cell
If he's sick, he'll come to the hospital
I guess so
Ah there were 3 left
I wonder if he ate them all...
Huh?!
Bye
Where is he stayng?
Um... I did hear the hotel name...
Try to remember it
But,
I thought you didn't care?
Enough!
Edward hotel
Edward hotel huh
Was it Adrian hotel?
No, that's from Rocky
Victoria?
I think it was some aristocratic name...
Renoir... maybe that's a cafe?
Ouch
This way
Yes?
Doctor call
I did feel sick since the morning, but not enough to warrant a doctor call
Well just lie down
You gave me weird stuff...
I never said to eat them all
It's food poisoning
Please eat something light for awhile
I guess you're a doctor after all
Of course
What's this?
I don't even know if I'm going to get married or not
You don't have to go this far!
Who said anything about YOUR wedding?
Huh?
It's MY wedding
Yours?
I met her from the hiking club
She's a good person
Well you should've told me....
I wanted to tell you,
and get your approval
But you...
But you did really say...
Because you weren't willing to listen!
Congratulations
Can I go to the wedding?
You silly
That goes without saying
I set the date on the 20th so you can come
What?
How did you know I have off on the 20th?
I heard it while I was at the hospital
Now only your wedding is left
Here we go again...
Well, I'll get going
Kuwano-san,
For your help this time,
You thank him too
Thank you very much
I hope you find a good person...
Ah!
If it's ok, I can set up an omiai..
No thank you
Just because you're marrying,
plase don't pull other people in too
Bye
"Pull other people in" what the..
Mom and Dad's living space is in blue,
and the son's family is in yellow
How about here?
That's livingroom and kitchen
Um...
Livingroom and kitchen will be shared from the both sides
According to Kuwano-san,
with the proposed budget,
it wasn't enough to build two sets of kitchen and livingroom
That's right
Besides, in the house,
there should be a place where everbody can talk,
and maybe even argue
That's fine with us
Are we really short of budget?
We're absolutely short
What is it??
Today was Dad's wedding
Here's a present
He told me to give it to you
It's probably going to be one of those useless plates
Bingo!
Well it doesn't matter
It's just a courtesy
But I don't understand...
why he's marrying again
She's a really great person
I can understand why he'd want to marry
Well at that age,
you don't need to worry about the in-laws
About that...
her mother is very healthy
At 87, she's still kicking!
And she's really stubborn!
So whoever marries you will end up with...
a stubborn father in-law, a stubborn 87 year old grand mother
I guess that's true
Looks like it'll get harder for you to marry
Totally unnecessary concern~
Thank you
Good night
Ah, you're here!
You know, I was thinking...
About your father...
Don't you think he and Kuwano-san are alike?
Mmm.. there are subtle differences...
My Dad is stubborn
Kuwano-san is just cynical
Well they're both peculiar
I think it's your fate to meet these people
I'm going to wait...
to meet a normal person
See if you get married,
you need to be alert,
the water gets dirtier,
oxygen gets halved
It's better to be alone
Right?